beyondblue.org.au 2008-12-16

# beyondblue: the national depression initiative - Privacy

|  | | | Home|Depression|Anxiety|Bipolar Disorder|Postnatal Depression| |   
---|---|---  
  
| 

About us

| | | 

Get information

| | | 

Symptom  
Checklists

| | | 

Getting involved

| | | 

Research

| | | 

Media

| | | 

Get Help

|   
---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
  
Our programsOur missionWho we areOur HistoryOur PoliciesHistory of the _beyondblue_ logoAnnual Reports & Evaluation ReportFunding StructurePartnersJobs at _beyondblue_Frequently Asked Questions

Get InformationOrder _beyondblue_ ResourcesDownloadable _beyondblue_ Information resourcesInformation for Health ProfessionalsFurther ReadingMultimedia Library

Symptom checklistsDepression checklistsAnxiety checklistBipolar disorder checklistPostnatal depression checklist

Getting involvedCorporate and Community PartnershipsFundraisingDonationsMaking a BequestJoin usPersonal ExperiencesNational Reference Group blueVoices

Medical Journal of Australia Supplement - June 16, 2008 _beyondblue_ Victorian Centre of Excellence in Depression and Related Disorders Research Grant Round 2008: Applications Now ClosedExpert Working Committee Members 2008 _beyondblue_ Victorian Centre of Excellence Search for beyondblue Research _beyondblue_ Research Book 2001 - 2007CVD and Depression Strategic Research Program NOW CLOSEDbbVCoE Funded ProjectsNew ResearchResearch Topics of Interest Research Notice BoardCancer and Depression 2009 Funding Round - Now OPEN

News 2008News 2007Media contactsMedia ReleasesNewsletters _beyondblue_ National Advertising CampaignMedia articlesMedia reporting guidelinesMedia TranscriptsPosition statementsNews 2006News 2005

Get HelpFind a Doctor or other Mental Health Practitionerbeyondblue Rural Assistance Information Network (RAIN) MapLinks  
  
|   

| | Privacy| |   
---  
  
|  |  |  | | Home >>Privacy  
---|---  
  
Privacy  
Privacy  

**

**BEYONDBLUE PRIVACY POLICY**

**

**Purpose**

> At _beyondblue_ , your right to privacy is very important.  We respect the privacy of your personal information, and manage it according to the appropriate privacy laws.  These laws regulate how your personal information (including sensitive and health information) is handled throughout its life cycle, from collection to use and disclosure, storage, accessibility and disposal.   

**Responsible for Policy**

>  Business Finance Manager

**Policy**

> This policy sets out how _beyondblue_ manages personal information that it holds; and ensures _beyondblue_ is compliant with the Privacy Laws when handling your personal information.
> 
> This policy may change from time to time in accordance with business requirements.

****

********Procedure********

**

_beyondblue_ collects personal information directly from you (by telephone, letter, fax or email; supply of a resume; completing forms, etc.).  Personal information about you may also be collected from a third party; including, but not limited to, when we receive references, results of enquiries of former employers, results of medical test feedback, any complaint from or about you in the workplace, any information about a workplace incident in which you are involved.

**1.1               ****Collection of Personal Information**

  _beyondblue_ collects personal information about a number of groups, including customers, suppliers, employees, contractors and potential employees.  Subject to any exceptions in the Privacy Laws:

  * We will not collect personal information about you unless that information is necessary for one or more of our functions.

  * We will collect personal information about you only by lawful and fair means and not in an unreasonably intrusive manner.

  * We will not collect sensitive or health information about you without your consent **** unless that collection is otherwise permitted by the Privacy Laws.

  * We will collect l information directly from you where it is reasonable and practicable to do so.

  * When we collect personal information about you, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that you are aware of the purposes for which the information is being collected, the organisations to which we would normally disclose information of that kind, the fact that you are able to access the information in writing to the Privacy Officer.

  **1.2               ****Use and Disclosure of Personal Information**  

> We will use or disclose your personal information for the purpose for which it was originally collected (the "primary purpose").  (For example, if you provide us your contact details to request information we will use your contact details to supply the information). 
> 
> We may also use or disclose your personal information for a purpose ("secondary purpose") other than the primary purpose of collection where:

  *  the secondary purpose is related to the primary purpose (or is directly related, in the case of sensitive information or health information), and you would reasonably expect us to use or disclose your personal information for that secondary purpose; or
  * you have consented to the use or disclosure of your personal information for the secondary purpose; or
  * the use or disclosure is required or authorised by or under law; or
  * the use or disclosure is otherwise permitted by the Privacy Laws; 

**1.3               Security and Quality of your Personal Information **

> ****We are committed to ensuring that personal information is held securely, taking reasonable steps to:

>   * ensure that any personal information we collect, use and disclose is accurate, complete and up to date;
>   * protect the personal information that we hold from misuse, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure: and
>   * destroy or permanently de-identify personal information as required by the Privacy Laws, subject to other legal record retention requirements.
> 

> 
> You can help us to keep the personal information that we hold about you accurate, complete and up to date, by letting us know about any changes to your personal information, such as your name and address.

**1.4               ****Access to and Correction of your Personal Information**   

>  You have the right to access the personal information that we hold about you, subject to any exceptions in the Privacy Laws.   You may also request that personal information which we hold about you be corrected.   Any request would need to be made in writing to the Privacy Officer.
> 
>   If access to or correction of your personal information is refused, we will provide you with written reasons for the refusal.

**1.5               ****Commonwealth and State Government Identifiers**  

> Except to the extent permitted by the Privacy Laws, we will not use your Commonwealth or State government identifiers (such as a Medicare number or driver's licence number) as our own identifier for you nor will we disclose such identifiers to anyone else.  

**1.6               Anonymity **

            If it is lawful and practicable to do so, we will provide you with the option of not identifying yourself when entering into transactions with us. ** **

 **

* * *

**

****  **Definitions** ** **

****  **Personal Information:**

>  is any information or an opinion about you (whether true or not) from which beyondblue can determine your identity.   It may range from the very sensitive (eg. medical history or condition) to the everyday (eg. address and phone number).  It would include the opinions of others about work performance (whether true or not), work experience and qualifications, aptitude test results and other information obtained by beyondblue in connection with a possible work placement.  Personal information includes sensitive information.

**Sensitive Information:**              

> When personal information concerns certain matters, it is considered sensitive information when it is about an individual's racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, membership of political associations, religious beliefs or affiliations, philosophical beliefs, membership of professional or trade associations, membership of trade unions, sexual preferences or practices and criminal record. 

**Health Information:  **

> Health Information **** means personal information that relates to a person's health or to the provision of a health service to the person.

  **Concerns**

> If you have any queries about this policy or about how we handle personal information about you, or you have any concerns or complaints about the manner in which _beyondblue_ handles your personal information, please contact the Privacy Officer.
> 
> We may change this Policy from time to time, so please ensure you have a current copy of the policy.      
> 
> If you are not satisfied that your complaint has been adequately handled by beyondblue, you may refer the matter to the Office of the Privacy Commissioner on [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/).  

**Related Documents**   

**Legislation** ** **

__Information Privacy Act (VIC) 2000__

 __

_Health Records Act (VIC) 2001_

* * *

* _beyondblue_ respects your right to privacy when online. This website does not collect any identifiable information except in:

  * Collecting site statistics which gives us information about how this website is being used and the number of visitors we receive; 
  * The 'Personal Experiences' section where users may choose to submit a story for publication on the website; 
  * The 'Resources' section where users may request a range of promotional material (posters, pamphlets, etc); 
  * The 'Contact Us' section where users may request further information; 
  * The 'Site Feedback' section where users may choose to submit a form with their opinions about the _beyondblue_ website; and, 
  * The 'Join Us' section where users may choose to receive a newsletter or join the beyondblue blueVoices virtual network.   

**  
  
| |   
SearchGo  
  
---  

| Our ambassadors| |   
---  

 **Garry McDonald**

---  

---  
  
---  
  
---  
  
---  
  
| | Multimedia| | | |   
---  
  
| Play _beyondblue_ 's Bipolar Disorder TV advert  
---|---  
  
* * *

| Play _beyondblue_ 's Depression in men TV advert   
---|---  
  
* * *

| Play _beyondblue_ 's Postnatal depression TV advert  
---|---  

| |  Last updated Monday, 30 July 2007| |  **14,126** page views from 07 May 2007 to 16 Dec 2008  
---|---|---  
  
Contact Us|Links|About this Site|Disclaimer|Privacy|Copyright
